把你的大脑开到观影模式吧
Get ready to turn your brains to viewing mode
因为从上一集《终空》里我们得知
because, previously on "Final Space,"
盖瑞收到了一条紧急求救消息
Gary just received a Mayday call
发信人不是别人  正是奎恩
from none other than Quinn, the super-spicy captain
那个让盖瑞五年来魂牵梦萦的火辣女舰长
he hasn't stopped thinking about for the past five years.
真是个撸瑟啊！哈哈哈！
What a loser! Ha ha ha!
哦  而且奎恩正在从无疆守卫逃跑？
Oh, and Quinn is on the run from the Infinity Guard?
哇！事情变得有意思了
Whoa! We've had our fun.
你们准备好了吗
Get ready to have yours.
盖瑞  你还有6分钟氧气可用
Gary, you have six minutes of oxygen left.
不可能的
It can't be.
你要干什么  盖瑞？
What are you doing, Gary?
你觉得我要干什么？我要摄取它的能量
What do you think I'm doing? I'm gonna consume its power.
但是打开头盔会让你的内脏爆出来
But opening your helmet will blow out your internals,
这会造成即刻死亡
inducing instantaneous death.
这只是其中一个可能性
That's one possible outcome.
另外一种可能就是  我吃掉了饼干  它的能量
Another, I eat the cookie, and its power turns me
让我变成了一个高贵的  能在太空里呼吸的蝎狮
into a majestic space-breathing manticore.
蝎狮（manticore）：一种传说中的生物，有红皮、蝙蝠翅和蝎尾，且有无限食欲。
在你吃到饼干之前  你就会死的
You will die before you eat the cookie.
我有信心在死之前就吃完它
I'm pretty sure I could get it in there before I die.
这是不可能的  盖瑞
That is not possible, Gary.
我真的觉得我能做到这个
I really think I can do it.
我会把它弄进来  然后光速合上头盔
I'm gonna lob it right in and close the helmet super fast.
你做不到的  盖瑞
You can't, Gary.
你弄不进来  也合不上头盔  也吃不到饼干
No lobbing, no closing, no cookie.
鸭嘴兽字幕组出品
翻译 + 专访听译 + 校对 + 压制：Kyl
Final Space - Chapter Four
终空  第一季第四集
Sync & Correction by f1nc0 from Addic7ed.com
本字幕仅供学习交流  请于下载后24小时内删除
紧急求救  紧急求救！
Mayday, Mayday!
我是奎恩·厄尔冈  无疆守卫的一名舰长
My name is Quinn Airgone, a captain in the Infinity Guard.
我一直在调查引力干扰
I've been investigating a gravitational disturbance,
由此发现了宇宙里的一个缺口
which I now see is a breach in space.
很多人因此而死  我也快死了  除非...
Many people are dead, and I'm about to join them unless...
啊！有没有哪个白痴能听到我说话？！
Aah! Is there not a single idiot that can hear me?!
我能听到她
I can hear her.
宇宙史上最伟大的爱情故事
The greatest love story in the history of the universe
就要开花结果了
is about to blossom forth.
老兄  控制一下你的期望值
Yo, dude, just keep the expectations in check.
五年来  奎恩连一条消息都没回过你
Quinn hasn't responded to a single message of yours in five years.
- 人类都很忙的  比如我就很忙   - 五年的每天都很忙？
- People get busy. I'm busy. - For five years?
4年  11个月  零30天
4 years, 11 months and 30 days.
- 那就是五年了  老兄   - 也许是  也许不是
- That's five years, bro. - Maybe it is. Maybe it isn't.
- 那就是   - 但也可能不是
- It is. - But it could not be.
已锁定失控飞行器
Disabled transporter is now locked in.
正在派遣舰上机器人  以确保奎恩的安全
Dispatching SAMES to secure Quinn.
别跟我抢  HUE！
Over my hard nipples, H.U.E.!
如果有谁要去救奎恩的话  那就是我  舰长大人
If anyone is saving Quinn, it's me, the captain.
盖瑞  我第9045次告诉你
Gary, for what is the 9,045th time,
你仍然是个囚犯
you are still a prisoner.
我不同意
I disagree.
自从这起事件演化成了星际大麻烦
As soon as the crap hit the interstellar fan,
我就真的变成了舰长
I became the captain for real.
正在计算... 不可以
Calculating... no.
正在计算  可以  我要行使我的权力去救奎恩
Calculating, yes. I will use those powers to rescue Quinn.
你的刑期又加了一星期
One week has been added to your sentence.
你他妈的... 这... 这又是啥  HUE？
Frickin' what ... what ... w... what's new, H.U.E.?
这算是啥玩意？
What's new?
现在  在我拼尽全力拯救我爱的女人之前
Now, before I risk my life for the woman I love,
有人碰巧带着薄荷糖吗？
does anyone perchance have a breath mint?
- 给你  盖瑞   - 啊！哦！
- Right here, Gary. - Ach! Oh!
天哪  不  我正在杀掉我最好的朋友！
God, no, I'm killing my best friend!
让KVN来  我可以的
Let KVN get it. I can do it.
很接近了  就在这
I'm close. It's right there.
哇  KVN  离开这  离我远点  永远别回来！
Whoa, KVN, stay away, far away from me forever!
哦我的天哪！呃！
Oh, my God! Ugh!
啊！
Aah!
开启营救  开启宿命
Commencing rescue. Commencing destiny.
干得不错  我需要征用你的飞船
Nice work. I need to commandeer your ship.
我有三级优先权
I have a class-three priority.
奎恩  你和我上次见你的时候
Quinn, you look every bit as spicy
一样性感火热
as the last time I saw you.
- 好的谢谢  你是哪位？   - 哦嚯嚯！
- Great, and you are again? - Oh-ho-ho!
我多怀念你敏锐的智慧
How I've missed your razor-sharp wit.
不  说真的  我不知道你是谁
No, seriously, I have no idea who you are.
- 真的？   - 你不像我认识的任何人
- Really? - You resemble no one I know
- 所以  我真的不认识你   - 你是认真的吗？
- so, yeah, really. - Seriously?
- 我是认真的   - 哦我的老天哪  你真是深受健忘症之苦啊！
- Seriously. - Oh, dear Lord, you're suffering from amnesia!
我深受一场危机之苦  这场危机足以毁灭地球
I'm suffering from an emergency that's going to destroy Earth.
奎恩  你真的认为我会相信
Quinn, you really expect me to believe
你不知道我是谁吗？
you don't know who I am?
等等  我知道怎么提醒你
Hold on. I know how to fix this.
这是真实又纯粹的盖瑞
This is the real raw Gary.
一点都没提醒到我  不管你是谁
That didn't fix it, whoever you are.
利刃穿心啊
What a dagger to the heart.
我就是那个过去五年里
I'm the guy who, for the past five years,
每天都给一个女人发短片的人
has been sending daily documentaries
然而这个女人甚至都不知道我是谁！
to the woman who has no idea who I am!
哇  真惨  然而我一条都没收到过
Wow, that sucks. I never got any of them.
你能不能告诉我驾驶台在哪...
Now, if you could just show me where the bridge is...
没关系的  这就是人生啊
It's all good. Life, you know?
嗯  挺可爱的  不过有问题  有大问题
Hmm, cute guy, but issues, definite issues.
奎恩甚至都不知道我是谁！
Quinn doesn't even know who I am!
哦  不！哦！
Oh, no! Oh!
哦！呃！
Oh! Uh!
哦... 我可没想到会是这样
Oh... this is not what it's supposed to be.
哦我的天哪  太伤我心了！
Oh, God, it hurts so much!
哦  她甚至都不知道我是谁！
Oh, she doesn't even know who I am!
我需要把我的心情录下来！
I need to record my feelings!
奎恩  仅供未来参考
Quinn, for future reference,
假装失忆是一件很合理的举动
the decent thing would've been to fake amnesia.
我也会假装失忆的
I would've faked amnesia.
我知道的和我爱的人都会假装失忆
People I know and love all would've faked amnesia,
但你说说看
but you had to be honest.
你能举出一段建立在诚实之上的感情吗
Name one decent relationship that has ever been built on honesty.
你举不出来吧？
You can't, can you?
因为这样的感情是不存在的
That's because there aren't any.
我知道我在胡说八道
I know this doesn't make any sense,
但我现在真的需要找人说说话
but I really needed to talk to somebody right now,
而你是唯一一个能让我敞开心之钱包
and you're the only person I can open my heart wallet to
倾倒伤心钢镚的人了
and spend my hurt coins with.
- 杰瑞？   - 哦！杰瑞？
- Jerry? - Oh! Jerry?
你连我叫啥都不知道
You don't even know my name.
阿瓦卡多  他还好吗？
Avocato, is he all right?
- 一点都不好   - 你都知道阿瓦卡多的名字？
- No. - You know Avocato's name?
- 嗨朋友们   - 现在别闹  KVN
- Hey, gang. - Not now, KVN.
卡尔  汉克  奥尔森  面条
Carl, Hank, Orson, Noodles,
- 你们能给我和  呃...   - 盖瑞
- can you give me and, uh... - Gary.
...盖瑞一分钟吗？
...Gary a minute?
你在给谁录视频？
Who are you recording that for?
一个对我来说有很大意义的人
Someone who meant quite a lot to me.
希望有朝一日她能看见它
I hope she gets to see it one day.
你在宇宙这么远的地方  很多视频信息都传丢了
When you're this far out in space, most of that stuff gets lost.
我猜也是  你来这干什么？
Suppose it does. What did you come here for?
我只是想说  “谢谢你  盖拉德”
I just wanted to say, "Thank you, Gerald."
不客气
You're welcome.
盖拉德？他叫盖拉德吗？
Gerald? Is his name Gerald?
他一直在骗我们吗？
Was he lying to us this whole time?
我很懵  也许盖拉德是昵称吧
I'm confused. Maybe Gerald is a nickname.
也许他姓盖拉德
Maybe his last name is Gerald.
能解释一下吗  盖拉德  盖瑞  盖拉德
Help me to understand, Gerald, Gary, Gerald.
本飞船已被无疆守卫当局控制
This ship has been seized by the authority of the Infinity Guard.
卡尔  现在别闹  我这天过得很不好
Carl, not right now. I've had a bad day.
我现在真的不想抱你  卡尔
I am really not in the mood for a hug, Carl.
卡尔  够了  我很好  快离开我！
Carl, that's enough. I'm fine. Get away from me!
坏卡尔！坏卡尔！
Bad Carl! Bad Carl!
坏卡尔！
Bad Carl!
紧急情况  我们的原子动力反应堆已耗尽
Emergency. Our power reactor has been drained.
银河一号已失去动力
The Galaxy I is immobilized.
一条接管命令被载入了我的系统
A takeover command has been uploaded into my system.
我在努力抵抗它  但它最终会成功的
I am fighting it, but it will succeed.
- 好吧  呃   - 是无疆守卫
- Okay. Uh. - It's the Infinity Guard.
我们被黑了  出于某些原因
We've been hacked. For some reason, they're trying
他们想阻止我进行调查
to shut down my investigation.
- 真是一群混蛋   - 他们是来追我的
- What a bunch of nerds. - They're after me.
- 你？为什么？你这么完美   - 从哪说起呢？
- You? Why? You're perfect. - Where do I start?
地球正在被一个黑洞吸入
The Earth is being sucked into a black hole.
我自作主张  偷了一艘飞船  逃避了追捕
I went rogue, stole a ship, evaded arrest,
如果我再不从这艘飞船上下来  所有人都会死的
and if I don't get off this ship, everyone dies.
你个小狐妖哟！
You sly fox. Jelly!
嘿！天哪  好吧
Hey! Oh, my gosh. Okay.
抱歉抱歉  我想说的是“你个冰雪女神”
Sorry, sorry. I meant, "You icy minx."
哦  流血了！流血了！
Oh, I'm bleeding! I'm bleeding.
抱歉  那就“危险熊猫”？
Sorry, I meant, "Danger panda?"
哦！我们是在调情吗！
Oh! We're flirting!
我们在调情诶！太棒了！
We're flirting! This is great!
这是咱俩亲密关系的一大进展！
This is a good advancement in our relationship!
哦！哦我的天哪！好吧好吧  调情结束
Oh! Oh, my gosh! Okay. Okay. We're done flirting.
我们不闹了  简直像以前一样
We're not flirting, just like old times.
相信我  才刚刚开始呢
Trust me. This is just the start.
一架帝国巡飞舰马上就会来夺取这艘飞船
An Imperium cruiser will be on the way to seize the ship.
那就来啊  好像我们的麻烦还不够多似的
Well, welcome aboard. Like we needed more danger.
我们现在只能束手无策地坐在这  等着无疆守卫的人来抓我们了
Now we're just stuck here until the Infinity Guard captures us.
怎么才能让这辆小火车重新驶向安全港？
How do we get this choo-choo train back to Safetytown?
理论上来说  我们可以利用
Theoretically, we could harness the solar rays
那颗垂死恒星的太阳光线  不过太不稳定了
from that dying star, but it is highly unstable.
我们必须离开这里
We've got to get out of here.
我可以空降到足够近的地方
I could space-vault close enough to it
我需要一台VX-1光物质泵
with a VX-1 light-matter pump,
然后开始采集  再然后重启反应堆堆心
mine it and restart the reactor core.
- 我来吧   - 不  我来吧
- I'll do it. - I'll do it.
我会再救你一次的
I'll save you again.
- 没门   - 有门
- No way. - Yes way.
- 你？不不不  还是我吧   - 我！不  不是...
- You? No, no, no, me. - Me! No, not...
- 不  我来   - 我... 我来吧
- No, me. - I ... I will do it.
然后你就知道盖瑞·古茨比德是谁了
Then you will know who Gary Goodspeed is.
别担心  我经常做这些
Don't worry. I do this all the...
事————
ti-i-i-i-i-me.
他的确经常做这些事
He does do that all the time.
我要拯救飞船  我要拯救奎恩
I'm gonna save the ship. I'm gonna save Quinn.
我要掌握命运
I'm gonna harness the crap out of destiny.
月饼  咱们走！
Mooncake, let's do this!
Chuck, chuck, chuck, chuck, woo-hoo!
放点好听的  HUE
Play the good stuff, H.U.E.
可以启动推进器了
You're a go for thrusters.
♪ I spent a year out in the desert ♪
♪ 一年献给大漠 ♪
♪ I spent a year out to sea ♪
♪ 一年献给汪洋 ♪
♪ I spend the nights under the stars ♪
♪ 长夜献给群星 ♪
♪ Just dreaming of asleep ♪
♪ 只愿安睡不醒 ♪
那是啥？！
What is that?!
♪ I still question where I've been ♪
♪ 我依旧不知道  我身在何方 ♪
那颗恒星四周是损毁飞行器的坟场
The star is surrounded by a graveyard of destroyed vessels.
谢谢你了  HUE
Thank you for the heads-up, H.U.E.
你现在看到的  盖瑞
What you are seeing, Gary,
是“血色长枪”及其舰队的残骸
is the remains of the Scarlet Lance and its fleet.
上千人因此毙命
Thousands of souls were lost.
这里真的好乱啊 HUE
And it's messy. We got that part, H.U.E.
真的好乱
It's a mess all over here.
那边  我是说那边
There, over there, right here,
尤其是那里  其实到处都一样  到处都好乱
especially right here, everywhere, it's a mess.
Chookity.
快点  盖瑞  那颗恒星即将开始内爆
Hurry, Gary. The star is about to implode.
♪ Go on down ♪
♪ 引我前行吧 ♪
开始了  HUE
We're cooking, H.U.E.
能量已经接收
Power is being received.
机器人开始切门了
The SAMES are cutting through.
HUE系统已被侵占
H.U.E. system is overrun.
你们现在都是无疆守卫的囚犯了
You are all now prisoners of the Infinity Guard.
一架帝国巡飞舰即将前来逮捕你们
An Imperium will be here shortly to seize you.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你在干啥？
Whatcha doing?
没干啥  你懂的  当你的阶下囚而已
Not much, you know, mostly being imprisoned.
- 你像屎一样   - 闭嘴！
- You look like crap. - Shut up!
你什么时候都像屎一样  不过现在
You always look like crap, but right now, like,
更像是屎上摞着屎
you look like if crap built a house on crap.
闭嘴！闭嘴！闭嘴！
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
啊  干什么！
Ah, come on!
吃吧
Enjoy.
机器人们  去逮捕目标
SAMES, apprehend the targets.
如有所需  可以使用必要的武力
Use all force necessary.
我们什么时候破门而入只是时间问题了
It is only a matter of time before we break in.
快投降吧
Surrender now.
如果我们能进入HUE的主机
If we can get into H.U.E.'s mainframe,
我们就能重新控制飞船了
we can regain control of the ship.
呃  机器人挡住了我们出去的路
Ugh, the SAMES are blocking our way out.
- 那才是我们出去的路   - 嘿伙计们  我能关上HUE
- That's our way out. - Hey, guys, I can disable H.U.E.
我们得把最精锐的人派去干这个活
We need to send the best person for the job.
- 我去吧   - 我屁眼里有把钥匙
- I accept. - I have a key in my butthole.
我觉得派我最合适
I was thinking of me.
这就搞笑了  我觉得我才是最合适的
That's funny because I was thinking of me.
我能做到的  信KVN一次
I can do it. Embrace the KVN.
你都不是无疆守卫的一员
You're not even part of the Infinity Guard.
你可是把我们拉进这场风波的人
You're the reason we're even in this mess,
而我  才是把我们救出这场风波的人
and I'm the reason we're going to get out of it.
- 你懂了吗  宝贝   - 不许... 叫我... “宝贝”
- Got that, baby? - Don't... call me... "baby."
祝我好运吧  大家
Wish me luck, guys.
- KVN！KVN！   - KVN！KVN！
- KVN! KVN! - KVN! KVN!
KVN！KVN！KVN！
KVN! KVN! KVN!
舰长日志5397
Captain's log 5397 ...
我们找到一个小型生命体
We have found a life-form small in size.
博士们都说他们从没见过这种东西
The doctors tell me it's unlike anything they have ever seen.
我们称之为E-351
We're calling it E-351.
- 舰长  有人找你   - 接进来
- Captain, we're being hailed. - Link it through.
你好啊
Hello.
你找到了我一直在找的东西
You found something I have been searching for.
- 把它交出来！   - 舰长  他们攻进我们的舰队了
- Hand it over! - Captain, they're logging onto our fleet.
准备光折引擎！
Prepare the lightfold engines!
- 长官  他们开火了！   - 准备躲...
- Sir, they're firing! - Evasive...
啊！
Gah!
Chookity?
无论你去哪里  死亡总是紧随其后
Wherever you go, death follows,
而今  死亡也将攫住盖瑞
and it will make its way to Gary.
这里好热啊  HUE  HUE！
It's getting pretty hot out here, H.U.E. H.U.E.!
HUE？你能听见我吗？
H.U.E.? Can you hear me?
HUE？阿瓦卡多？
H.U.E.? Avocato?
奎恩？有人能听见我吗？！
Quinn? Anybody?!
KVN？
KVN?
好吧  是时候在爆炸之前回去了
All right. Time to head back before this star implodes.
月饼去哪了？月饼！
Where's Mooncake? Mooncake!
盖瑞
Gary.
外面怎么有条毛毛虫？
Why is there a caterpillar out here?
你咋离我脸这么近呢  漂亮的小东西？
What brings you, noble creature, so close to my face?
等等  为啥我在和一条毛毛虫说话？
Wait. Why am I talking to a caterpillar?
显然  我产生了幻觉
It's obvious. I'm hallucinating.
啊！
Aah!
哈！
Huh!
我的儿子今天怎么样啊？
How's my boy doing?
- 好极了   - 爸？
- Great. - Dad?
真令人不安
That's unsettling.
新帝国T3巡飞舰
The new Imperium T-3 Cruiser
将会把我们带去下一个银河系
will bridge us to the next galaxy,
倒计时开始  十...
and the countdown has begun. 10...
嘿  你想看外面的发射吗？
Hey, you want to watch the launch outside?
九...
...9...
当然了！
You bet!
...七  六  五...
...7, 6, 5...
- 爸！   - 睁大你的眼
- Dad! - Keep your eyes open.
发射地点就在那
It'll be taking off right over there.
...三  二  一
...3, 2, 1.
- 总有一天  我也要做这个   - 真的？
- One day, I'm gonna do that. - You are, huh?
真的  我要经历许许多多自己的冒险
Yeah, I'm gonna have a whole bunch of adventures.
- 许许多多？   - 许许多多
- A whole bunch? - Bunches and bunches.
为什么要让我看这个？
Why are you showing this to me?
你说啊  你个臭毛毛虫！
Answer me, you drug-dealer caterpillar!
哦！
Ohhhh!
我想起来了
I remember this.
- 儿子...   - 我想和你一起去
- Son... - I could come with you.
我真想让你和我一起来啊
There's nothing more in the world that I would want,
不过这次不行  小家伙
but not this time, little buddy.
这次我得自己一个人去  你可能不懂
I have to do this one alone. You won't understand,
不过你要知道  我做的一切都是为了你
but know that I'm doing this for you.
- 你能给我个承诺吗？   - 好的
- Can you make me a promise? - Yeah.
答应我  你以后要经历自己的冒险
Promise me you'll have your own adventures.
- 我会的   - 许许多多的冒险
- I will. - Bunches and bunches.
给你这个  我不在的时候让这个小东西陪着你吧
Here, this fellow will look after you while I'm gone.
- 他叫什么？   - 月饼
- What's his name? - Mooncake.
KVN  我知道你想做什么  KVN
KVN, I know what you're trying to do, KVN.
一切关掉我的尝试都会失败的  因为你就是个撸瑟
Every attempt to disable me will fail because you are a loser.
这可说不好  HUE  我非要把这个插进去不可
Can't talk, H.U.E. I have to insert this thingy in you.
哈！
Huh!
我不会让你插进来的
I will not let that insertion happen.
这是最后一次机会  请立刻停止一切行动
This is your last chance to cease all action.
停下
Stop.
呃！
Ugh!
没人相信你
No one believes in you.
滚吧  你简直在浪费生命
Go back, you waste of life.
快啊  KVN！
Hurry, KVN!
哦  啊  哦
Oh, ah, ooh.
正在重启
Booting back up.
所有系统均已脱离无疆守卫网络
All systems now independent of the Infinity Guard network.
啊！啊！
Aah! Aah!
啊  KVN胜利了！
Aah. KVN is victorious!
KVN成功了！干得漂亮  KVN
KVN did it! Good job, KVN.
盖瑞永远不会相信这个的
Gary is never going to believe this.
系统已重新激活  你们好
Systems have been reactivated. Hello.
很高兴你回来了  HUE
Nice to have you back, H.U.E.
很高兴我回来了  不过不好意思  我还有坏消息
Nice to be back. Sorry to be the bearer of bad news,
我们还处在极度危险之中
but we're still in extreme danger.
无疆守卫那些混蛋找到我们了
Those dickheads from the Infinity Guard found us,
盖瑞那边还没有回复
and Gary is not responding.
盖瑞  你在哪？
Gary, where are you?
你的辐射值已经接近致命量了
Your radiation levels are becoming critical.
你必须马上离开
You must leave now.
约翰·古茨比德这次的任务是
John Goodspeed is on a mission
调查造成太空异常的
to investigate a shift in the gravitational constant
引力常数的变化
that's creating an anomaly in space.
- 别逼我看这个了   - 你必须得看
- Don't make me watch this. - You have to.
爸！
Dad!
警告  警告
Warning, warning,
辐射值已经达到92%
radiation levels have reached 92%.
Chookity, pok, pok.
盖瑞  请立即返回飞船
Gary, return to the ship immediately.
我监测到恒星里的巨幅波动
I am detecting massive fluctuations in the star.
HUE  准备光折引擎
H.U.E., prime the lightfold engines.
- 盖瑞怎么办？   - 我们没时间了
- What about Gary? - We don't have the time.
如果我被无疆守卫抓住了  数十亿的人都会死的
If the Infinity Guard catches me, billions of people die.
- 我喜欢杰瑞   - 是盖瑞！
- I like Jerry. - Gary!
没错  盖瑞  我也不想丢下他
Right, Gary. I don't want to leave him,
但这远不是一个个体的问题
but this is bigger than one person.
辐射值已达到98%
Radiation levels have now reached 98%.
醒醒  盖瑞
Wake up, Gary.
恒星随时可能爆炸
The star could explode at any moment.
盖瑞  我们需要你马上回到飞船上！
Gary, we need you to get back to the ship now!
盖瑞  恒星马上将要变成超新星了
Gary, the star is going supernova.
盖瑞  快他妈给我醒来  马上回来
Gary, wake the hell up, man. Get back to the ship pronto.
- 快啊   - 我的妈耶！
- Come on. - Oh, my gram!
快啊！快快快快快快快快快快快！
Go faster! Go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
哦！哦哦哦！这下麻烦了！哦不！
Oh! Oh, oh! This is troubling! Oh, no!
不！哦！哦！
No! Oh! Oh!
- 他来不及回来的   - 他来得及
- He won't make it in time. - Yes, he will.
抱歉  奎恩  我们要等盖瑞
Sorry, Quinn. We wait for Gary.
好吧  我们等盖瑞
All right. We wait for Gary.
银河一号  准备好被登船吧
Galaxy I, prepare to be boarded.
妈的开门啊！
Open the freaking door!
光折飞船  HUE！
Lightfold the ship, H.U.E.!
INSIDE THE EPISODE AFTER CREDITS
泽塔克隆  阿尔法
总司令流放地
成功了
It works.
爸  这是我的坐标
Dad, these are my coordinates.
快来找我  我的意思是  等你有空的时候
Come find me, I mean, at your leisure,
不过还是希望你能快点
but, like, for me, preferably fast. That'd be great.
爸  这是我的坐标
Dad, these are my coordinates.
快来找我  我的意思是  等你有空的时候
Come find me, I mean, at your leisure,
不过还是希望你能快点
but, like, for me, preferably fast. That'd be great.
是谁重新黑进了HUE  控制了机器人？
Who reverse-hacked H.U.E. and the SAMES again?
- 是我   - 当然了  每次你都这么说
- I did. - Right, you keep saying that,
不过不可能是你
except there's just no way that's possible.
哦  其实这次真的是他
Oh, yeah. He's truth in' it.
所以对于这个引力干扰  你有什么见解吗？
So what can you tell me about this gravitational disturbance?
你为什么想知道这个？
Why do you want to know?
我觉得我爸和这个有关系
I think my dad has something to do with it.
- 等等  你爸是谁？   - 约翰·古茨比德
- Wait, who's your dad? - John Goodspeed.
你爸是约翰·古茨比德？我终于想起来了！
Your dad was John Goodspeed? Now I remember!
你就是那个五年前拼命追着我  让我请你喝酒
Five years ago, you're the guy who kept asking me for a drink,
然后炸飞了92艘帝国巡飞舰
then blew up 92 Imperium Cruisers
外加一家墨西哥小餐馆的人！
and a small Mexican family restaurant!
是是是！那就是我！
Yes, yes, yes! That's me!
- 你果然记得我！   - 确实如此
- You do remember me! - I do.
现在  把你的手指头从我脸上拿开  不然我就撅了它
Now get that finger out of my face, or I'll snap it off.
我喜欢你的语气
I like how you speak words.
啊！
Aah!
Sync & Correction by f1nc0 from Addic7ed.com
NEXT WEEK...
幕后专访
INSIDE THE EPISODE
盖瑞见到奎恩的时候  发现她完全不知道他是谁
When Gary meets Quinn, and he realizes that she has no idea who he is.
这太打击了  真的太打击盖瑞了
It's crushing, just absolute so crushing for this guy.
他给她发了五年的消息
He's been sending these messages to her for five years.
他以为她收到了那些消息
He thinks that she's been getting them,
但是并不知道为什么她不回信
doesn't really know she hasn't been responding though.
更何况奎恩是盖瑞有联系的唯一一个人
And this was like the only person that he connected to,
虽说盖瑞并没有真的联系上她
but he didn't connect with her at all.
所以  他得回溯一切进展
So it's kinda have to, like, retrace all the steps
重新想一下要怎么和这个真人展开联系
and figure out how to actually make connection with the real person.
我体会不到这种感觉  这种事从来没在我身上发生过
I can't relate to that, that's never happened to me.
至于月饼  他总是一副“Chookity”的样子
With Mooncake, he was always kind of like "Chookity".
但是他有感情
He feels everything.
有点怪怪的伤心感  因为世上最珍贵最可爱的小东西
And so it's sad in a weird way that this most precious cute thing in the world
竟然同时也是最可怕的杀手
is also the most deadly thing.
月饼所到之处一片伤亡  他当然能感觉到愧疚
Mooncake definitely feels guilt when he leaves a trail of death,
这也是他为什么惹人怜爱
but it's what makes Mooncake so loveable.
又伤心  又悲惨  又搞笑
It's sad, it's tragic, but it's also funny.